SENTHIL SELVAKUMAR

https://www.linkedin.com/in/senthil-selvakumar-9815a8125

201-993-2892

https://github.com/Senthilselva/

senthilselvak@gmail.com

Profile Page

Full Stack Web Developer, with passion for all aspects of web development. Extensively well versed with both frontend and backend development, specializing in JavaScript, JQuery HTML, CSS, Bootstrap and Media Queries, Node.js and have an innate love for learning new NPM packages. Familiar with MVC file structure. Have strong experience with Relational Databases - MySQL and Oracle and also have a good understanding of Firebase database.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Materialize, JavaScript, jQuery, Firebase, JSON, REST APIs, AJAX, MVC file structure, Node.js, Express, Handlebars, MySQL, Mongodb, ReactJS

EDUCATION

Rutgers University Certificate, Full Stack Web Development

Fairleigh Dickinson University, New Jersey Masters of Science, Computer Science

WORK EXPERIENCE

AJS Associates Inc

2009 - Present

Office Manager /I.T. Specialist

Planned and implemented computerized paper flow system of current files on all employees, bids, contract information, material cut sheet, bid documents etc. that helped the company to be more organized. Prepared invoice, certified payroll and processed payroll on a weekly basis. Managed daily Administrative affairs and communication

Remin Technologies, LLC

2005 - 2009

Founder and President

Founded and managed a C to C consulting corporation and hiring firm specializing in training and employee placement in the software industry. Developed strong industry related problem solving skills as well as strong business and management capability.

Cap Gemini 2000 - 2004

Software Developer

Worked on various telecommunication project as consultant for AT&T and Lucent Technologies. Used C++, Oracle and Unix

APPLICATIONS BUILT

Resume Builder

• Application designed for young adults searching for volunteer, community service, internship, and

(C)

SENTHIL SELVAKUMAR

- part-time positions
- Returns search results based on specific categories selected from user profile creation
- Provides email when position is selected
- Uses MySql, Sequelize, Handlebar, Node.js, Express, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Nodemailer, and REST API, JSON, JavaScript and JQuery
- https://github.com/link-here / Heroku hosting

Face the Music

2016 Full Stack Developer

- Built a mood based play-list generator
- Solely responsible creating firebase login, the embedding filepicker API which can be used for selecting a picture from the computer or take a picture from the camera, Firebase storage to store pictures and firebase database to store user information, for data validation using JQuery and JavaScript on my team
- https://github.com/link-here / Firebase hosting